Jerry Ryle

I am an engineering leader with a strong software engineering background and a breadth of experience in product development. I build and manage teams that solve challenging engineering problems with a user-centric approach. I work closely with finance, operations, sales, and marketing to ensure that we meet our business objectives while we ship products that people love.

Experience

Alpine Health, Mountain View, CA **V.P. Engineering**, 2017-2018

- Hired and led a cross-functional team of engineers and consultants to build a revolutionary consumer health device
- Produced our key patent application
- Bootstrapped the company: set up payroll and benefits, hired development partners, created our interview process, defined our peer review and feedback process, codified our development methodology, and made coffee
- Lead the team in creating a form-factor prototype for user testing and fundraising, optimized with computational fluid dynamics, and informed by clinical science

Mindtribe Product Engineering, San Francisco, CA Partner and V.P. Engineering, 2001-2017

- As a partner and vice president, I was responsible for business development, sales, program management, process development, strategy, hiring, and mentorship
- Built Mindtribe into a 40-person, world-class engineering consultancy
- Brought Agile values to hardware engineering, enabling rapid product development
- Was the primary thought leader for improving our engineering methodology
- Scaled numerous startups from MVP to mass-market

Key Mindtribe projects that I managed (many more on my portfolio site at jerryryle.com):

Stealth Company, Encrypted Communications Device, 2015-2016

- Led a cross-functional team to take a complex, consumer electronics device for encrypted voice communications from concept through manufacturing in less than a year
- Took over management of two engineering teams, an electrical consultant, an audio consultant, an app development firm, a security auditor, and a contract manufacturer in the Philippines
- Solved technical challenges relating to security, testability, and manufacturability

Adobe, Project Parallel, 2012

- Led a team of developers and designers to create Line, Adobe's Ink and Slide showcase app
- Taught the rapid development methodology that we used on Line to Adobe's other app teams

Square, Stand, 2012

- Led a cross-functional team of engineers to deliver Stand, Square's point-of sale solution for brick-andmortar retailers
- Structured and ran this program from concept through manufacturing
- Set clear priorities for the team, which allowed us go from concept to shipping product in less than a year

Education

California Polytechnic State University, San Luis Obispo, CA | B.S., Computer Engineering, Class of 2000

Patents

US20190000599A1 (pending) - Systems and methods for personalized oral irrigation

US9262777B2 - Card reader with power efficient architecture that includes a wake-up circuit

US9286635B2 - Method of transmitting information from efficient communication protocol card readers to mobile devices

US9495676B2 - Method of transmitting information from a power efficient card to a mobile device

WO2012177370A1 - Wireless input device